#### **GURPREET SINGH**

gurpreetsingh05.in@gmail.com | <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gurpreet-singh-05">https://github.com/singhguri</a>

# **Summary:**

Computer science professional with experience in software development and strong leadership skills. Avid believer and programming enthusiast who constantly strives to learn new technologies and looks for ways to improve in this rapidly growing industry.

#### **Education:**

### **Bachelor of Technology- Computer Science Engineering**

Aug 2017 - Jun 2020

• Courses: Database, Programming, Computer Networks, Mathematics, Data Structures and algorithms

Diploma Aug 2014 - July 2017

#### **Technical Skills:**

Familiar with: C#, ASP.Net MVC, Dot Net Core, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

Databases: SQL Server 2012/2014/2016, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB

• Tools: MS Office- MS Word, Powerpoint, Excel, Microsoft Outlook

Platforms: Windows, Linux, Ubuntu

# **Professional Experience:**

### Software Engineer, Arethos Pvt. Ltd.

Mar 2020 - Present

### > ALS WMS

- Technology stack used is .Net Core API, FTP service and Angular 8.
- Leading a team of 10 for the project involving the management of goods and services, in a warehouse like Amazon, or Costco.
- Working on encoding and decoding EDI format files.

#### > ALS ELD

- Technology stack used is .NET and BING maps API along with vanilla JavaScript.
- Worked in the Geofencing and Map module and was responsible for writing clean code using top-notch methodologies.
- TCP/IP Service
- Fetched data from the OBD Device (attached to vehicles) through cloud and stored them in JSON files.

#### ALS Tracking

- Worked on a project which involves Truck/Trailer tracking to find information about which geofence it currently is in.
- The tracking is real-time with interactive UI of Angular.js

### > ALS Dispatch

 Collected dispatch information like consignee, shipper details, and cost of the loaded material using the technology stack C#.net, MVC framework.

### > ALS Smart Track

- Lead the project where I was involved in tracking the truck containers using SignalR, which is a library for Microsoft ASP.NET.
- Developed developing the core functionality as well as deployed it on the server.

#### **➤ Virtual Box Office**

- Built an API for the project, using c#.Net and Angular.
- Enhanced the functionality of the existing API and performed load testing.

#### Software Engineer Intern, HCL Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Jan 2020 - Feb 2020

#### > NLP Search Engine

- Built an NLP search engine using Python.
- The dataset was made out of a csv file and accessed using Pandas module.

#### > Responsive Web Pages

- Worked on making the web pages responsive (automatically adjust and adapt to any device screen size).
- Used technologies like HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.

# **Academic Experience:**

# ➤ Face Detection – Python, Open CV, Anaconda

- OpenCV is a Library which is used to carry out image processing using programming languages like python.
- Utilized OpenCV Library to make a Real-Time Face Detection using webcam as a primary camera.

# ➤ Encryption Algorithm – Python, Anaconda

 Created an encryption algorithm to scramble, or encrypt, data and then used a key for the receiving party to unscramble, or decrypt, the information.

### Corona Virus India Tracker – Python, React JS, Selenium, Anaconda

- Created a corona virus tracking website which tracks the latest cases of corona virus in different states of India.
- Displayed the number of people cured and number of deaths due to the pandemic. This website updates twice a day.

## **Achievements and Certifications:**

- 2 Month internship from HCL Technologies Pvt. Ltd.
- Hackathon winner at Arethos Pvt Limited
- Volunteer lead at Life Saves NGO, organized various food and clothes donation camps.
- NSS coordinator, lead several blood donation camps and social events
- Core committee member of an organization in Arethos, which dealt with planning and organizing events.
- Attended CCNA 90 hours training with national certification.
- Participated in "Student parliament" organized by CSE department in March, 2018.
- Third position in "Brain Teaser An Inter Quiz, organized by MEC Club in October, 2017.

# **Interpersonal skills:**

- Confidence.
- Ability to handle the problems with positive attitude.
- Good presentation skills.
- Team-Spirit
- Innovative Explorer
- Willingness to work and learn
- Keen Learner and a good listener.